AARON VONTELL

860-805-0050 vontell@mit.edu github.com/vontell

229 Vassar Street Cambridge, MA 02139

Profile

I am a sophomore at Massachusetts Institute of Technology, pursuing a degree in Electrical Engineering and Computer Science. I have five years of computer programming experience, mainly in Java and Android. I also completed a summer internship at Cigna on an Application Developer team. I am currently working with two startups, Parcio and UpStudent.

Experience

Android Application Developer, Cigna; Bloomfield, CT — Summer 2014 Duties included developing proof-of-concept software and Android applications using the Java programming language, in conjunction with external libraries and devices. Multiple projects were completed in accordance to a schedule, and collaboration and teamwork were used throughout each project.

Web Application Developer, Cigna; Bloomfield, CT — Summer 2015

Duties included creating web applications using next generation web technologies (HTML5, CSS3, AngularJS) for integration into a larger web application. Work also included writing many PL/SQL stored procedures and writing scripts to give websites offline capabilities.

Lead Software Developer, Parcio; Boston, MA — 2014 - Present Duties include developing an Android and iOS application with the startup Parcio. The application includes work with Google APIs, MapQuest Open APIs, Android SDK, iOS development, and a custom REST API. Also requires multiple meetings with city officials and the Department of Transportation. See more at parcio.com

Chief Technology Officer, UpStudent; Cambridge, MA — 2014 - Present Duties include guiding and tutoring students through the college application process, through a detailed lesson plan, simulated interviews, and post-acceptance meetings. Also includes all development of our company's website using Bootstrap and hosting through Github. See more at myupstudent.com

Education

Attended University High School of Science and Engineering, 2010 - 2014

40+ college credits from University of Hartford during high school, 2011 - 2014

Currently enrolled in Massachusetts Institute of Technology, 2014 - present

Pursuing Electrical Engineering and Computer Science Major, with a focus on Quantum Computing, Concentration in Chinese

Technical Skills

Java Programming (4+ years)

Android Programming (Including multiple APIs) (2 years)

Extensive Git/SVN experience

Python (1 year)

Experience with RESTful services (Weather Underground, Google Maps, MapQuest, and more)

Experience in PL/SQL, HTML, CSS, Objective-C, Swift, JavaScript, AngularJS, and Spring Tool Suite

Project Management (From a leadership role on a FIRST Robotics team for 6 years)

Photoshop CS6

Autodesk Inventor Professional

Soft Skills

Extensive Experience with the Agile Development Process

Experience working in a large corporation (35,000+ employees)

Worked in development groups of 3-5 developers and 15-20 developers

Enjoys writing documentation and commenting code

Volunteer Work

Treasurer of National Honor Society (2013)

Volunteer at Imagine Nation Museum (2010-2012)

Cavalier Club (Community/Fundraising Club) (2013-2014)